

SENIOR CONSULTANT · TECHNOLOGY · 6.0 YEARS EXPERIENCE

Deloitte Consulting India Private Limited - Bangalore, KA 560037, India

🗷 shubhamgulati91@gmail.com | 🌴 shubhamgulati.com | 🖸 shubhamgulati91 | 🛅 shubhamgulati91

Summary

6.0 years experienced Senior Consultant with a demonstrated history of working in the management consulting industry. Experienced in development of micro-service architecture based application back-ends using Java, Spring framework, and Agile Methodologies. Skilled consulting professional with a Bachelor and Master of Technology Integrated Degree focused in Computer Science Engineering from Jaypee Institute Of Information Technology, Noida, NCR, India.

Work Experience _____

Deloitte USI (Deloitte Consulting India Private Limited), 4 yrs 4 mos

Bangalore, KA, India

SENIOR CONSULTANT, 5 MOS

9th May 2022 – PRESENT

· Responsible for training and mentoring new hires on SpringBoot, SQL, Git and other project related tools and technologies.

Consultant, 2 yrs 9 mos Sep. 2019 – May 2022

- Implemented RESTful and GraphQL APIs for applications based on microservice architecture using Spring Boot, Spring Web, Cloud, Data, JPA,
 Hibernate, and related Spring framework and Apache libraries.
- Designed server-side pagination, aspect logging and transaction tracing frameworks for applications built from ground up.
- Designed data migration APIs with async and parallel execution to migrate millions of records from mainframe to modern application deployed in the cloud.
- Implemented backend for a M&A HR application with features such as on-boarding entities from mergers and acquisitions, reduction management, and sending digital letters to employees from templates through Adobe DocuSign.
- Conducted multiple hand-off knowledge transfer sessions with client and application maintenance teams after successful deployment of features and applications to production.

BUSINESS TECHNOLOGY ANALYST, 1 YRS 4 MOS

Apr. 2018 - Aug. 2019

- Implemented backend for a HR Portal with more than 20 microservices performing highly critical computations such as capturing employees data from workday, determining annual bonus, career progressions, and annual equity distribution.
- Implemented reporting backend services for various modules using Apache POI libraries that are used by HRs to download and share reports with the department.
- Implemented API exposed microservice module the in Customer Support Portal to allow high rank officials to perform administrative tasks such as granting permission to manage and documents and access to sensitive software.

CGI Inc. (CGI Information Systems and Management Consultants Pvt. Ltd.), 1 yrs 9 mos

Bangalore, KA, India

ASSOCIATE SOFTWARE ENGINEER, 1 YRS 9 MOS

Aug. 2016 - Apr. 2018

- Developed a system downtime management module with features such as orchestrating shutdown and startup of apps and messaging queues for maintenance mode using JMX operations.
- · Modernized legacy monolith based applications to modern microservices based Spring Boot applications.

Publications

An efficient technique to control road traffic using Fuzzy Neural Network System

Noida, UP, India

AUTHOR, DEPARTMENT OF CSE, JAYPEE INSTITUTE OF INFORMATION TECHNOLOGY UNIVERSITY, NOIDA, INDIA

October 2014

• IEEE Journal – Xplore Digital Library Link

Education

Jaypee Institute of Information Technology University

Noida, UP, India

BACHELOR & MASTER OF TECHNOLOGY, DUAL DEGREE IN COMPUTER SCIENCE AND ENGINEERING, 75% AGGREGATE

June 2010 - June 2015

Tiny Tots School

Bikaner Bovs School

Sri Ganganagar, RAJ, India

C.B.S.E. - A.I.S.S.C.E. - 12^{TH} Standard, 72% aggregate

Bikaner, RAJ, India

C.B.S.E. - A.I.S.S.E. - 10TH STANDARD, 88% AGGREGATE

2007 - 2008

2009 - 2010

Professional Projects

Support Portal Deloitte USI

JAVA, MICRO-SERVICES, SPRING BOOT, JPA, SQL, REST APIS, GIT, GERRIT, JIRA

2019 - 2020

- Responsible for development of Support Portal, and marketplace order fulfillment orchestration layer for a major industry leader in enterprise security, networks and silicon chips manufacturing.
- Purpose of the Spring Boot module include fetching order data from upstream ERP source, orchestrate order fulfillment, downstream updates and case management from an easy to use dashboard.

Enterprise HR Portal Deloitte USI

JAVA, MICRO-SERVICES, SPRING BOOT, HIBERNATE, SQL, REST APIS, GIT, GERRIT, JIRA, SPRINT PLANNING

2018 - 2019

- Responsible for development of HR Portal for a major industry leader in telecom, networks and silicon chips manufacturing. Delivered a set of 10 Spring Boot modules comprising of 700+ REST endpoints.
- Purpose of the Spring Boot modules include capturing employees data from Workday ERP, determining annual bonus, career progressions, annual equity distribution, on-boarding entities from mergers and acquisitions, and reduction management.

Enterprise Customer Support Portal

Deloitte USI

JAVA, MICRO-SERVICES, SPRING BOOT, REST APIS, GIT, GERRIT, JIRA

2018

• Responsible for solo end-to-end delivery of a back-end only Spring Boot module comprising of 15 REST APIs for administrative and executive operations such as granting permission to manage and access software and documents to users.

Enterprise M2M Data Services Platform

CGI

JAVA, SPRING BOOT, SHELL SCRIPTING, JUNIT, POWER MOCKITO, ZOOKEEPER, NAGIOS, DEVOPS

2017

- Responsible for solo end-to-end delivery of a back-end only Spring Boot based system downtime management module using JMX operations and maintenance mode.
- Responsible for modernization and DevOps of legacy web apps to modern Spring Boot based modules.

Academic Projects

Study of load balancing approaches in distributed computing environment

P.G., J.I.I.T. Noida

C++, OPENMPI

2015

· Study based on survey, comparison and analysis of performance of various load balancing approaches in distributed computing environment.

Intelligent Traffic Control - Decision Support System

U.G., J.I.I.T. Noida 2014

2013

JAVA, MACHINE LEARNING, NEURAL NETWORKS

• Proposed, implemented and validated a novel technique to control road traffic using a pre-trained Fuzzy Neural Network Tool.

Web Proxy Server U.G., J.I.I.T. Noida

Python, Computer Networks

· Implemented a Python based Proxy Server for caching, filtering and blocking web requests and data elements.

Skills

Languages Java, SQL, Basic JS, HTML & CSS, Basic Shell Scripting

Frameworks Micro-services, Spring Boot, Spring Cloud, Spring Web, Spring Data, JPA, Hibernate, GraphQL, Apache POI

Other technologies Cloud Native Development, GCP, Docker, Kubernetes, Jenkins, JIRA, Git, GitHub